





n @joãoteixeira96

https://github.com/joaoteixeira96



Cybersecurity



PROFILE

Since I was a kid, I always wanted to catch bad guys, but in a smart way! So cybersecurity was the deal. I'm a curious person with team spirit, openminded and eager to learn, having several years of experience in programming and security gained through personal, academic, and company projects. Looking for a role where I can grow and continue to learn from experienced people.

EDUCATIONAL

NOVA College of Science and Technology

Master of Science in Computer Science.

 Attended from Sept. 2019 to Sept. 2021, specializing in computer network, cryptography, network security and distributed systems.

NOVA College of Science and Technology

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.

• Attended from Sept. 2015 to April 2019.

SKILLS

Knowledge Areas

- Vulnerability Management.
- Risk Assessment.
- Application Security.

Programming/Web Development

 Java, Python, SQL, C, Kotlin, JavaScript/ReactJS, HTML/CSS.

Tools/Frameworks/CTF

 Kali linux, Metasploit, Nessus, BurpSuite, Nmap, ZAP, Wireshark, John, Hydra, sqlmap, TOR, Docker, Azure, Git, OWASP, NIST, OSSTMM, MITRE ATT&CK.

EXPERIENCE

Security Delivery Associate

Accenture Portugal | July 2021 to present.

- Vulnerability Management
 - Assess, validate the risk and prioritize remediation of the vulnerabilities.
 - Coordinate responsibilities with the different project teams.
 - Create a monthly executive report.
- Application Security
 - Application testing and conducting security assessment for web applications using SCA, SAST and DAST scan tools & manual penetration testing
 - Executive report & presentation of the findings.

Full Stack Developer Intern

EInnovator - Enterprise Middleware, LTD | Oct. 2018 to Feb. 2019.

- Developed a microservice solution using Spring Framework that allowed companies and employees to review, edit or revoke product contracts.
- Agile methodology (Jira).

Member of the organization committee

NLNF - FCT NOVA IT Club | Sept. 2018 to July 2019.

• Organized Talks, Workshops and a 2-day Hackathon.

Member of the organization committee

JORTEC - FCT NOVA IT | Sept. 2017 to July 2018.

• Organized Workshops and a 3-day Hackathon.

PROJECTS

Thesis – Strengthening of Tor Against Traffic Correlation with K-Anonymity Input Circuits

 Built a mechanism to protect Tor users against traffic correlation attacks, using combined techniques: Kanonymity routing strategy and overlaying traffic morphing